Abdul Rahim

- Islamabad, Pakistan
- +923435154517
- abdul.rahimk21@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/rahimabdul

Experience in the complete Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) with Analysis, Design, Development, Testing, Implementation, and Maintenance of various web, windows, and Enterprise Information Systems. Accelerated delivery and deployment by streamlining delivery modules. Ready to start as a developer with my knowledge, skills, and industry experience to be more productive for an esteemed organization.

KEY SKILLS

- API & Database Design
- Agile Development

IT Consultant

- DevOps & Cloud Management
- Front-End & Back-End Development
- Microservices
- Linux & Windows
- Research & Development
- Problem Solving
- Adaptability
- Collaboration
- Technical analysis

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MFSys Software and Systems (Pvt) Limited Islamabad, Pakistan

http://mfsys.com.pk/

January 2020 – Present

January 2017 – April 2018

May 2014 – January 2017

- Principal Software Engineer
 Senior Software Engineer
 - Responsible for complete software development life cycle and solution delivery using a team of highly specialized resources.
 - Collaborated with senior management within the organization and implemented the budget planning process to ensure more effective and efficient use of available resources.
 - Improved all aspects of the technical development cycle, including functional and technical product specifications, testing and quality assurance, documentation, configuration management, and version control.
 - Analyzed user needs and software specifications to determine the feasibility of the design.
 - Developed and customized software for client usage to optimize operational efficiency.
 - Educate developers on how to commit their work and how can they make use of the CI/CD pipelines that are in place.
 - Educate and train new resources on the organization's business and technology domains.
 - Owned accountability for formulating and tracking project execution and implementation plans. Led team to develop processes and applications as per financial policy while examining users.

Capital University of Science & Technology Islamabad, Pakistan

https://cust.edu.pk/

Technical Team Lead

November 2018 – December 2019

- Developed project plans, goals, identifying resources needed.
- Developed schedules and methods for measuring results.
- Assembled and coordination among project team members; assigning individual responsibilities.
- Managed GitHub repositories and permissions, including branching and tagging.
- Have built Docker images and written Docker files which can be used to automate all developer tasks.

- Managed all phases of the project to ensure on-time completion
- Planned the preparation and dissemination of project communications.
- Managed quarterly reports and deliverable documentation.
- Designed and implemented project core modules
- Automated build and deployment using Jenkins to reduce human error and speed up production processes

Finman Group Islamabad, Pakistan

http://www.consultfinman.com/

IT Consultant

June 2018 – November 2018

- Coordination and consultation in the selling, implementation, and after-sale support to the clients of SmartHCM (an HR- Hire to Retire Solution).
- Efficiently direct a team of technical and customer service on a line of Finman Group IT products and services.

Aga Khan Agency for Microfinance Islamabad, Pakistan

https://www.akdn.org/

Senior Software Engineer

Feb 2011 – April 2014

- Designed and implemented project core modules.
- Worked with cross-functional teams including quality assurance and customer support teams.
- Direct coordination with product development and customer support team to accomplish the customer's new requirements.
- Led project implementation from gap analysis till sign-off the project to fulfill customer satisfaction.

HALKAR Inc. Islamabad, Pakistan

http://www.halkar.com/

Senior System Engineer

August 2010 – February 2011

• Efficiently managed all phases of the software development life cycle and support to deliver direction to system programmer and development teams.

The First Microfinance Bank Ltd. Islamabad, Pakistan

https://www.fmfb.pk/

Software Engineer

July 2007 – July 2010

- Planned and developed components of banking software of the organization, including deposit, remittances, loan process, mobile /online banking, application administration, and back-office.
- Designed and coding project core modules.
- Worked with quality assurance and customer support teams.
- Coordinated and collaborated with software development and IT operation teams to achieve the digital requirements of the bank operation and finance departments.

EDUCATION

National University of Modern Languages, Islamabad, Pakistan	2005 - 2007
Master in Computer Science	CGPA: 3.1
Major: - Software Engineering	
Allama Iqbal Open University, Islamabad, Pakistan	2001 - 2004
Bachelor in Information Technology	CGPA: 3.0

Major: - Information Technology

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript, Typescript, Python

Frameworks: EJB3, Spring Boot, Angular, Express.js (NodeJS), and Apache Drill

Database Engine: IBM DB2, MySQL, PostgreSQL and MongoDB

Operating Systems: Linux (Ubuntu, CentOS), Windows

Cloud Technologies: Amazon Web Services (EC2, S3, RDS, lambda)

IDEs: Eclipse, NetBeans, VS Code, Android Studio, Jupyter Notebook

Application & Web Servers: WebLogic Server, Apache Tomcat, Nginx

Messaging & Build Tools: Apache Kafka, Apache Maven

Configuration & Continuous Integration: Ansible, Jenkins

Containerization: Docker, Kubernetes

Bug tracking: JIRA, Mantis Issue Tracking, CA Rally

CVS, SVN, GITHUB, Bitbucket **Version Control:**

Libraries & API: FFmpeg, iText, Apache FOP, YouTube API, JAIN SLEE, Log4j

Reporting Tools Crystal Reports, BIRT,

Agile & Kanban Tools: JIRA, Trello, **SIP Servers:** Kamailio **In-Memory Storage:** Redis

Testing & Automation: Swagger, Postman

PROJECTS

3GPP-IMS compliant E2E Mobile IPTV solution for 4G/LTE Network

http://www.openimstv.org/

Research and development project funded by Ignite Pakistan to Capital University of Science and Technology (CUST) in collaboration with MobileVAS (SMC-Pvt) Ltd to achieve the following points.

- 3GPP IMS and ETSI IPTV Standards Compliant SDP Platform
- Delivery of adaptive IPTV Streams based on network conditions, Set-top box metrics and Head End Server Performance
- Context-Aware and Personalized BC and VoD Services
- Support for IMS Enabled Authentication and Authorization interfaces for the IPTV Subscribers
- Support for IMS Compliant Billing and Charging interfaces for charging the subscribers
- IMS /SIP Compliant Android & iOS based IPTV set-top box
- The proposed IPTV SDP will implement following pre-integrated services as a part of this project
- Live Programming or Broadcast Channels (BC), Video on Demand (VoD) /Stored Video Delivery
- Electronic Program Guides (EPG)

Tijari (Digital Service Solution)

https://tijari.life/

Tijari is a digital service solution developed by MobileVAS (SMC-Pvt) Ltd. Available on Google play store and App store. Provides the following services

Shopping

Food

Mobile Wallet

Ticketing

Mobile Top-ups

Payment

Implementation of Core Microfinance & Banking System

Successfully implemented "Core Microfinance & Banking" (Banking ERP Solution) in

- Soon valley development program, Khushab Pakistan.
- Al Wataniya Microfinance Institution, Syria.
- The First Microfinance Foundation Egypt.
- The First Microfinance Bank Ltd. Afghanistan.
- The First Microfinance Bank Ltd. Tajikistan.

CiiHive (Core Microfinance and Banking CM&B formerly)

https://dev.mfsys.com.pk/

MFSYS CiiHive is a next-level digital core solution. With CiiHive it is a one-step Digital Transformation that would provide your customers a seamless digital experience.

- One platform, multiple touchpoints, PC, Tablet, Mobile, POS, etc.
- One integrated system, everything in one place
- Highly scalable and efficient
- KYC and AML regulatory compliant
- Design product and service offering on the fly Product and Service design including checking, savings, personal, Business, Deposits, Term Deposit, Loans, fund transfer, forex & investment
- Flexible and multiple Chart of Accounts, highly flexible transaction matrix and sub-ledger options
- Transaction management support all types of transactions, auto, manual, fixed, single, multiple, compounds
- Intelligent analytics and insight data representation and Reporting
- Real-time 24×7
- Highly secure and platform agnostic
- Built-in workflows and standard process options
- Fully support for Open APIs

Marketing & Implementation of SmartHCM

http://www.smarthcm.com/

SmartHCM is complete HR hire to retire solution a product of SofDigital Systems.

- Response to RFPs as a partner in the north region, Pakistan.
- Demonstration of software to clients.

Halkar (Platform as a Service)

http://www.halkar.com/

Cloud-based solutions for Financial Management, CRM, Banking, Education & Training, and Help-desks. Individual, Corporate and Government customers can manage all their daily end to end business activities from Halkar's one single dashboard.

TRAINING/CERTIFICATE

- ✓ IBM DB2 9.7 Bootcamp and Oracle to DB2 Migration Clinic | 4 Days technical workshop at FAST-NU
- ✓ Python & Data Science | 8 weeks course from Data Analytics, Islamabad
- ✓ I'll be Agile 2019 | 10 hours training from DatumSquare, Islamabad

REFERENCE

Provided upon request